Saurabh Burman

A full stack web developer in JavaScript technology having 5 years of work experience. Also interested in System Design and Devops. I am good at analytical and logical skills required to solve complex algorithms. My goal is to become an expert in web technologies. I like to try and solve challenges I face and I have great patience to find the solution of any given problem.

"

" : " burman.saurabh123@gmail.com"

"web": "https://burman-saurabh.github.io/my-profile/"

"奮":"9986498724"

Work Experience

08/2015 - 03/2018

Bangalore, India

Senior Systems Engineer

Infosys Ltd.

Accomplishments

Worked as an agile team member for offshore costing application team of an American clothing and accessories retailer GAP which basically is a tool where client and their vendors work together for costing of the products. Worked as a Quality Analyst with Jira. Also worked in Service Now for maintenance and continuous feedback and was also involved in continuous monitoring. Also worked for automations for routine tasks such as server re-starts, report-generation for Business Analyst team etc. Had exposure to MongoDB and REST architecture in the microservices based applications.

10/2013 - 07/2015

Bangalore, India

Systems Engineer

Infosys Ltd.

Accomplishments

Worked in masking team to encrypt customer's sensitive data of a bank to protect data with Mainframe technology.

04/2013 - 09/2013

Bangalore, India

Systems Engineer Trainee

Infosys Ltd.

Accomplishments

Underwent generic training covering Core Java, DBMS and OS concepts. Cleared stream training in Core Java, JSP, JDBC and SQL Server.

Education

- B.Tech (Electronics & Telecommunication),
 C.V. Raman College of engineering,
 Bhubaneswar.
- 6.7 CGPA, 2008-2012
- Class X (CBSE) 79.6%, 2005

Class - XII (CBSE) 80.2%, 2007

Achievements

Dhyan Chand Award by NIIT

Awarded to people who comes under top 1000 in aptitude and logical reasoning examination called NITAT held at national level.

Interests

Developing brain and board games | Space & Extraterrestrial life | Plays | Supporting needy

Personal Traits

Creative Skills | Patience | Do not give up easily

Technical Skills

	1	I	I	1
JavaScript				
CSS3				
HTML5				
Angular				
MongoDB				
Node.js				
Express.js				
TypeScript				

Other Technical Skills

- Bootstrap, SASS
- Socket.io
- Mongoose
- Angular Material , ng-bootstrap
- Version Control : GIT
- Postman
- OS : Linux, Windows
- Docker, Jenkins, Kubernetes
- Splunk
- Nagios
- Jira
- Service Now



Saurabh Burman Bangalore, 15/11/2021